这是普通高等学校招生全国统一考试
英语科听力部分，请看听力部分第一节。
第一节。
听下面五段对话。
每段对话后有一个小题，
从题中所给的
三个选项中选出最佳选项，并标在试卷的相应位置。
听完每段对话后，你都有十秒钟的时间来回答有关小题和阅读下一小题。
每段对话仅读一遍。
例如。
现在，你有五秒钟的时间看试卷上的例题。
你将听到以下内容：
Excuse me, can you tell me how much the shirt is?
Yes, it's nine fifteen.
你将有五秒钟的时间将正确答案，画在试卷上。
衬衫的价格为九磅十五便士，
所以你选择
项，并将其。
画在试卷上。
现在你有五秒钟的时间
阅读第一小题的有关内容。
Oh my, my car broke down and I have to meet my aunt at the railway station before
noon. You're lucky, I can drop you off on my way.
Did you hear that Mr.
Peterson is coming next week, Gordon?
Yes, so I called all the department heads to my office this morning.
We need to give him reports on our program.
I hope you like the book I lent you.
I wasn't sure if you'd be interested.
I had the same doubt at first, but once I started, I simply couldn't put it down.
What is going on?
It's May and we still have to warm clothes.
Well, there's some good news on the radio.
You probably can wear shorts tomorrow.
第一节到此结束。
第二节，听下面五段对话。
或独白。
每段对话或独白后有几个小题，
从题中所给的
三个选项中选出最佳选项，并标在试卷的相应位置。
听每段对话或独白前，
你将有时间阅读各个小题，
每小题五秒钟。
听完后，各小题给出五秒钟的作答时间。
每段对话或独白读。
读两遍。
听下面一段对话，回答第六和第七两个小题。
现在你有十秒钟的时间
阅读这两个小题。
Well, how about going skating?
I'd like to, but my knee hurts too.
Harry, stop making excuses.
You're just lazy.
No, I'm not.
You know, there's a basketball match on TV today.
Let's just stay home and watch it.
Okay, you stay, and I'll play with Helen.
Harry, let's play some ping pong today.
I'd love to play a set or two, but my right arm hurts.
I've decided to stop playing ping pong until it feels better.
Well, how about going skating?
I'd like to, but my knee hurts too.
Harry, stop making excuses.
You're just lazy.
No, I'm not.
You know, there's a basketball match on TV today.
Let's just stay home and watch it.
Okay, you stay, and I'll play with Helen.
听下面一段对话，回答。
答第八和第九两个小题。
现在，你有十秒钟的时间
阅读这两个小题。
What do you want to
There's a good art film at the Greenhouse Cinema.
Let's see. It starts at 6.15.
I don't think we can get there in time to see the beginning.
How about the action film at the New State Cinema?
It starts at 6.50.
Perhaps the 7 o one at the UME Cinema is even better.
It stars Jackie Chan.
Okay, that's fine.
I like him too.
What do you want to do tonight?
How about going to the cinema?
I should be home from work at 5.45.
Then we can go out and eat before we see a film.
What do you want to see?
There's a good art film at the Greenhouse Cinema.
Let's see. It starts at 6.15.
I don't think we can get there in time to see the beginning.
How about the action film at the New State Cinema?
It starts at 6.50.
Perhaps the 7 o 'clock one at the UME Cinema is even better.
It stars Jackie Chan.
Okay, that's fine.
I like him too.
What do tonight?
should work at 5 see
听下面一段对话。
回答第十至第十二三个小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题。
Hey, Lucy. Do you have some time to talk about next week's trip with me?
Sure, Dave. Okay.
So, we're leaving on Monday from Hartsfield International Airport and returning on
Friday. Do we take ourselves to the airport?
Maybe we need to a taxi or just go by bus.
No, we don't have to.
The company car will pick us up and take us there.
Oh, that's good.
When? Our flight leaves at 11 a.m.
so they should pick us up between 8 and 9 a Besides, the company pays for our trip
including hotel and food.
How much will that be?
Well, New York is a pretty expensive city so each of us will get $200 a day.
Oh, okay. Thanks for telling me that.
You're welcome. Hey, Lucy.
Do you have some time to talk about next week's trip with me?
Sure, Dave. Okay.
So, we're leaving on Monday from Hartsfield International Airport and returning on
Friday. Do we take ourselves to the airport?
Maybe we need to book a taxi or just go by bus.
No, we don't have to.
The company car will pick us up and take us there.
Oh, that's good.
When? Our flight leaves at 11 a.m.
so they should pick us up between 8 and 9 a.m.
Besides, the company pays for our trip including hotel and food.
How much will that be?
Well, New York is a pretty expensive city so each of us will get $200 a day.
Oh, okay. Thanks for telling me that.
You're welcome. Thanks
听下面一段对话，回答
第十三至第十六四个小题。
现在你有二十秒钟。
的时间阅读这四个小题。
welcome. Please sit down.
Let's see. You're Mr.
Smith, is that correct?
Yes, John Smith.
And you're interested in this job?
Yes, I am.
I'll graduate from college the coming June.
My major is Chinese.
I see. Have you ever done any work in this field?
Yes, I used to be a tour guide for Chinese travelers.
Good. Now, how much money do you expect to have for a year?
From what I've read, it seems that a starting pay would be around $12,000 a year.
Here you would start at $10,500 for the first year, a kind of training period.
Then you would go to $15,000.
That sounds fair enough.
What do you think are the chances for me to get a job here?
Well, I'm talking two, three people today, and four tomorrow.
We'll be hiring two people.
You'll hear from us sometime next month.
Good luck. And thanks for coming in today.
Please sit down.
Let's see. You're Mr.
Smith, is that correct?
Yes, John Smith.
And you're interested in this job?
Yes, I am.
I'll graduate from college the coming June.
My major is Chinese.
I see. Have you ever done any work in this field?
Yes, I used to be a tour guide for Chinese travelers.
Good. Now, how much money do you expect to have for a year?
From what I've read, it seems that a starting pay would be around $12,000 a year.
Here you would start at $10,500 for the first year, a kind of training period.
Then you would go to $15,000.
That sounds fair enough.
What do you think are the chances for me to get a job here?
Well, I'm talking two, three people today, and four tomorrow.
We'll be hiring two people.
You'll hear from us sometime next month.
Good luck. And thanks for coming in today.
听下面一段独白，回答
第十七至第二十四个小题。
现在你有二十秒钟的时间。
阅读这四个小题。
Thank you. Well, I'd love to share with my personal opinions on city life and life
in small towns.
I grew up in a small town until I was 18, and then moved to a big city.
So, I have experienced the good and bad sides of both.
I never thought that I would like living in a big city, but I was wrong.
After 10 years of living in one, I can't imagine ever living in a small town again.
Surely small towns and big cities both have some problems in terms of transport.
In a small town, you have to own a car to make life comfortable.
You can't get around without one, because there isn't any kind of public transport.
Big cities generally have heavy traffic and expensive parking, but there you have a
choice of taking public transport, which is cheaper than driving.
So, if you don't have a car, you'd better live in the city.
I also love the exciting life in big cities.
I can always enjoy a lot of films, concerts, and other wonderful shows.
However, these things are not common in small towns.
The final thing I like about large cities is that you can meet different kinds of
people. However, you seldom find such a variety of people in a smaller town.
I think that living in an area where everyone was just like me would quickly become
dull. Of course, safety should be considered, and that's one area where small towns
are better than big cities.
Still, I would rather be a bit more careful and live in a large city than to feel
safe but dull.
Well, I'd love to share with you my personal opinions on city life and life in small
towns. I grew up in a small town until I was 18, and then moved to a big city, so I
have experienced the good and bad sides of both.
I never thought that I would like living in a big city, but I was wrong.
After 10 years of living in one, I can't imagine ever living in a small town again.
Surely small towns and big cities both have some problems in terms of transport.
In a small town, you have to own a car to make life comfortable.
You can't get around without one, because there isn't any kind of public transport.
Big cities generally have heavy traffic and expensive parking, but there you have a
choice of taking public transport, which is cheaper than driving.
So if you don't have a car, you'd better live in the city.
I also love the exciting life in big cities.
I can always enjoy a lot of films, concerts and other wonderful shows.
However, these things are not common in small towns.
The final thing I like about large cities is that you can meet different kinds of
people. However, you seldom find such a variety of people in a smaller town.
I think that living in an area where everyone was just like me would quickly become
dull. Of course, safety should be considered, and that's one area where small towns
are better than big cities.
Still, I would rather be a bit more careful and live in a large city than to feel
safe but dull.
第二节到此结束。
现在你有两分钟的时间，将试卷上的答案
转涂到客观题答题卡上。
watching! Thank you for watching!
You